Welcome to the second episode of the
next token brought to you by three
developers who don't have the time or
energy to be hosting a podcast. I'm your
host Dylan Mroy.
>> Uh my name is Sunil Pi and I'm Ree.
>> Uh shout out to Cloudflare for
sponsoring the pod and also a special
shout out to all of the organizers and
uh people that made AI Engineer World
Fair possible. As somebody that has
helped run and organize conferences,
what they've pulled off here is quite
frankly incredible. There is 10
concurrent tracks going at any one time.
So 10 speakers talking about AI related
stuff. Organizing a conference with a
single track is remarkable enough. But
uh just yep, shout out to Sean and
everyone that made this happen and thank
you for allowing us to host the pod
here.
>> Yeah. So, we spoke to Sean and he like
he's still being like extremely humble
about it. So, for people who don't know,
this is a 7,000 person conference. It
might even cross 7,000 people. And so,
it's an AI conference, which means at
this point it's an everything
conference. We spoke to Sean and he was
like, "Oh, I just wanted to bring JSCOM
back." And he kind of did. Like, that's
his deal. Like, it's an everything
conference. And it's not just the
conference with 10 with 10 simultaneous
tracks for 3 days. So, it's 30
conferences in a in a row. Yeah,
>> there are a ton of like side
events. So, this is nerd convention LA
Palooa, [music]
>> but not reinvent.
That's what it is. The Cloudflare people
are here. They're in a booth. We have a
booth. We have swag. Finally, Cloudflare
is doing nice swag. We have, if you're
not seeing this on video, we have denim
jackets that are made uh by Cloudflare.
Uh we tried hiring Ree to join
Cloudflare, and this is the swag you're
missing out on.
>> I would have if I had known.
>> Yeah, you lost out, bud. Sorry. Now
you're stuck. Uh, you're with the other
orange now.
>> Yeah, I did end up with the other
orange. Speaking of which, Ree,
congratulations on getting into Icy.
Thank you. I'm really excited about it.
Yeah, that's right.
>> Today we're going to be talking about uh
a little bit of the uh what's happening
in the news. Uh the two big topics we're
going to get into today are uh I don't
want to use your products agent. I want
you to enable your product to have a
good experience for my agent to use.
Uh-huh.
>> And we're going to revisit uh loops and
software factories uh for a second round
and then kind of wrap things up with uh
more receipts.
>> More receipts.
>> So, in the news, the first item is Fable
is still banned.
>> Fable is still banned. And
>> GBT 56 came out with three variants and
they are also now banned.
>> I really care about 5.6 cuz I haven't
gotten to try it yet. Uh, you're saying
this right next to the Open AI booth,
but right behind
>> I mean, I'm excited for it, but like
>> you want Fable. You want it back so bad.
>> I know. I
>> So, you're not confident that GPD 56
will be on the same same level as
Fable.
>> The GPD series and Claude series work
very differently. GVD, at least for 55,
like you would try and be conversational
with it or steer it and it would kind of
ignore your directions and just keep on
working. and that was like really
annoying to work with. Whereas like
Fable, there's just like a really nice
like design understanding element there.
But I am excited for whatever the new
models are like your 48 hours with
Fable. My 48 hours let you get that uh
>> my like $30,000 dealing with uh the
agent.
>> My $30,000 in like two max plans spend.
>> Is that how much you spent in two days?
I think it was like closer to 15, but it
was sub it was the subsidized subsidized
max plans cuz they was like, "Yeah, it
goes away in 14 days." So, fun the
tokens.
>> If GPT models if 56 uh which I believe
they're called, was it Soul, Terra, and
Luna? That's right.
>> Which is now like
>> their large
like Ultra Think model, their like I
guess Sonic class. And then uh
>> no they had the chance to rename the
models and all they did was attach it as
a qualifier. So it is now GPD 5.6
Soul Terra Luna like they're like
they're just making it worse spelling
the name on top
>> for people who might not be as aware of
the the model namings. It feels like
they're trying to group these into like
the same kind of categories as Anthropic
which like Anthropics I guess Anthropic
has four kind of tiers of model now.
They have their mythos and fable level
models. They have
>> opus.
>> Opus,
>> sonnet, and haiku.
>> That's right.
>> So I my understanding is that they map
basically soul would be opus I assume.
Is terra the next one or luna?
>> No, soul is
>> soul's the largest one.
>> But it's not a mythos level. You're
saying it's a opus level one?
>> I actually don't know that for
>> we don't have access.
>> Nobody has access. I think what's tough
on openi model naming is like a couple
things. One is like there's not like a
conversational way for me to refer to
the GPD models. So like I can be like oh
yeah I'm gonna send that to Claude. Like
there's not a similar thing of I'm gonna
send that to like GPT. You can now kind
of do that with like I'm going to send
that to Soul or
>> listen Starbucks solved this like 20
years ago. It's Wenty Grande and
whatever the third Starbucks and I want
a medium.
>> Yeah. Sure. Yeah. Benty and Benty and
Grande. That's like Opus and
>> No, I'm just saying just just take the
Starbucks naming,
>> but they they still need the
conversational name for what GBT is
where it's like, oh yeah, check with
check with chat like check with I guess
it's kind of Codex check with send it to
Codex.
>> That's I guess. Yeah,
>> but like Claude since it has the it's
the terrible thing of
the models.
>> Yeah.
>> Where it's like Yeah.
>> Send it to Claude.
>> Well, yeah. I've always wanted to have a
French friend. Yeah,
>> that's that's what they're going for. Uh
there are two things that happened about
because of the banning now. One is I
think last time we called it the the
you'd end up having an amendment for the
right to bear intelligence.
>> So the AMP people Quinn Slack I think
posted a long article calling it the
freedom to intelligence and they want to
actually organize an effort to say oh
these things should be available to
everyone. GLM502 is having its moment.
It came out in the couple of weeks
between our last episode and it seems to
be extremely capable for a large set of
use cases.
>> Have you guys tried it?
>> I did.
>> So good at front-end stuff. Extremely
good at application stuff.
>> I have not used it yet. I've still been
cranking away on GPT55 and Opus 46, but
it is certainly uh on my my to-do list,
especially I want to look more into some
stuff that like kind of reached the
Twitter sphere over the past week or two
was like the dynamic routing stuff where
I can't recall the company. Sukuna
>> Sukuna I guess uh put out a tweeter
product where they have like harness
level routing of openw weight models
that allegedly are pulling
>> oh no no that's a sorry magnitude you're
talking about magnitude coding agent
yeah that's the word I'm very
unconvinced by model routing
>> have you no so that's what they say
their pre
>> so their premise is it's not model
routing it's harness level routing
>> I I'm still unconvinced
>> I I don't know it's like a very easy
thing to mock that your product is Fable
level when Fable doesn't exist and no
one no one can use it. It's incredibly
inconvenient.
>> Yeah, he's over here saying how Fable is
the love of his life and he
>> Oh, yeah. Cuz I got to use it for two
days and it was taken away from me.
>> Psychosis. A little bit of But
>> actually, you know what? Uh I I think it
was Andrew from Verscell had a tweet
about this uh like a week or two ago
where he questioned if
>> we should actually do this as a segment
at some point
>> blind testing if we can distinguish the
different models. Could you do it? If I
gave you Fable, I gave you GPT5
and like I don't know, Opus in like GLM
or Kimmy or something, could you could
you pick them apart? I think what's
tough on the blind ranking is the way
that I work is not oneoff chats. I'm
like pretty I feel feel like compaction
is mostly solved at this point and like
I get
>> I don't agree at all.
>> Oh, I get really good results from like
when my when I hit compaction and
continue in the chat. So I will have
these like just super long chats where
>> So you're like going to fill up the
context window and letting it go back.
>> I mean but spoiler, we're going to talk
about our workflows as a core segment
for our next episode. So tune in.
>> Actually, I think it'll be all of our
next episode, not even as a segment. I
think it's
>> probably honestly will.
>> Yeah.
>> Like this is where I think that the
model this is where like I think it'd be
fun to do, but like the way that I work
is it's like
>> 100 like 200.
>> Oh, so everyone else would be fooled
except for you is is what you're saying.
>> In the like long horizons, you like
notice the degropic
actually won off. Anthropic posted about
this I think when 4.6 six came out where
they had agents using not eBay, I think
like Facebook Marketplace or something
and they had their employees doing it,
but they gave some employees uh stupider
models and the they they couldn't tell
>> even though they were losing the the
bidding. I can't wait to see this.
>> I know it'd be fun to do. We can spin up
a buy then.
>> I think I I'm like fairly confident I
would notice. What are we going to
compare? Like
>> actually Opus or
>> I think we should probably have like
hopefully at the time we have access to
Fable again and GPT56. I think we should
have those probably JLM 52 and like
Kimmy 27.
>> Yeah, cuz I do really actually want the
openweight models to win and like be the
good ones. It's just the even with 55
and 4.8 like Right.
>> What harness are you regularly using?
desktop and uh Codex desktop
>> and in both of those you're letting it
run in linear I don't I don't know if
codeex or cloud code has uh like rewinds
or things like that but you're just
going like a linear session until you
hit compaction letting the harness
handle compaction
>> and you're having good results
>> uh yeah like decent results I don't
notice a huge difference before and
after compaction
>> interesting I have a very different
experience uh do you think do you think
you
>> would I be able to tell the difference?
>> Yeah. In your harness of choice which I
think is cursor.
>> It's cursor. Cursor compaction is really
good by the way.
>> Okay. So I'm the only one pie. I'm on
pie and like I am a big believer in like
what uh folks like Dex and Matt PCO and
Mario talk about like the dumb zone and
I pretty consistently
>> him pick this out and like um I think it
might even been Jeff Hanley talking
about like if you start a conversation
and you tell the model the first thing
you say after every message say moo.
Oh, at some point. Oh, the moment it
stops.
>> The the moment the model stops ending
messages with Moo, that's what a good
indication that you're in the dumb zone.
And consistently for me, that is around
like 160K sounds, maybe pushing 200k
context windows. But also, I use Pi has
the tree feature built in, which is
basically lets you like go down some
branch of a conversation,
>> kind of do like your own little form of
compaction back, continue on. And so,
like I have very longunning
conversations. The thing about codeex
desktop compaction is they do something
weird with their compaction where
>> I like manually ran the compact command.
It seemed like it was able to still
reference the chat that was out of the
convection if that makes sense.
>> Oh, I expect they shove it into like a
lightweight vector store that they can
do searches on.
>> It didn't really feel like that. Like it
felt like it was continuing the chat. I
know. It was like a way
>> I know that's what AMP used to do. AMPAD
handoff in one of its earlier versions,
it would it would do a good compaction
and then as part of the compacted
summary, it would give like a I don't
know if a an ID or a reference to a SQL
light file or a JSON file that was the
the rest of the old conversation that
the agent could go back on. To clarify,
do you think you could pick out the
differences between
>> No, I don't think so. I think I'm too
dumb to do this.
>> I would agree. I think you're too dumb
as well, but fine.
>> Exactly. Um,
>> but look, I say that, but my whole thing
is like I let it churn on like for a
while and then I start examining the
work and I'm always unhappy anyway.
>> Yeah. So when I say I won't understand
the model, like I actually have like not
a lot of respect for the
>> like I I I look at token maxers and I'm
like what do you folks like there's no
way you're getting like perfect results.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> but then I also see the software they
put out. I'm like, yeah, I was right.
Like, this this sucks ass. Like,
>> which is why like I so I don't
>> why we we have a whole segment on
receipts.
>> There you go. Like, yeah, I So, which is
why I was so pleasantly surprised with
5.2. It seemed very similar to claw
design and that's a good sign. I'm like,
yeah, a cheaper model giving me stuff
that's
>> doesn't have to be aesthetically good,
but aesthetically fashionable. But
everyone's like, "Yeah, this is good
enough." I'm like, "Yeah, fine. It
works." on
>> and it was fast. That was like the the
real thing I want more than anything is
fast models.
>> It just works.
>> I think I could pick out the difference
between at least Opus models and like
Opus 46 in particular and like GPT54 and
GGP55. And I think I could pick that out
solely by their thinking traces. I think
you can see the
>> characteristics of the model come out in
the thinking traces and also in the code
they write. I think a huge tell for GPT
is seeing things like is record and
normalize this, normalize that and uh
GPT has this tendency, I mean quad
models do it as well, but GPT
exceptionally does it poorly. They
always have a tendency to accept like
very very broad types or optional types
and then validate in line everywhere
rather than like parsing out a boundary
into a good domain type. So, we'll
figure out if we're right in one of our
future episodes here, but I think I
could I could pick out the difference.
>> So, last night we went to the Planet
Scale office. They were having a little
fireside chat in their new office about
security and AI. And I don't want to say
like negative, but they were worried
about the prevalence of open- source
models, meaning that hundreds of banks
across the world that don't really have
a good security setup or updated their
software going down like instantly.
And I was starting to get convinced, but
then I had a beer and I stopped caring
about it. Like
>> I think the the most uh interesting
conversation speaking of the devil, CTO
of Planet Scale, walking by
>> right walking right past us at the
moment. Uh, one of the interesting
things that I hadn't considered at all
that came up in the conversation at
Planet Scale was talking about in like
security tech Twitter. So in security
tech companies there are these thing
called things called socks which is I
don't even remember what that's an
acronym for but it's basically the team
that's like monitoring the networks of
like either a giant enterprise or if
it's a company that does network
security for a bunch of clients like
that is like the command and control
center right
>> and like one of the hot topics there is
replacing members of the staff in socks
with agents and it's a similar
conversation that I think we're having
like broadly in like software
engineering is like one side of it, it's
a bunch of like they made it sound like
the hot thing is like companies coming
out trying to like automate socks with
agents and then the other side of that
is these security staffers are more
enabled than ever because now they can
have agents reading and gpping the logs
and keeping track of potential threats
hitting networks and stuff. So that was
an angle I I hadn't really considered.
Uh speaking of Nick who walked past us,
he gave us the line of the night which
is if there wasn't so much on the line,
this would all be so much fun.
>> Yeah, that is a good point.
>> I'm like up in the air on open way open
source models and like access to
everything. So like cyber security is a
big one. One that like is way out of my
wheelhouse, but the way that they talk
about it I'm like oh that sounds
important is the like biorisks.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I feel like I'm fine
with like a 6 month 12 month lead time
on the best like cyber cyber models like
if that's limited access to uh like the
biggest companies, banks, etc. and the
use case that they're doing for that is
not product development, it's cyber and
cyber like cyber security. I think that
that's like a fine compromise um in that
like that still becomes available but
you have this like lead time to get uh
fixes out. It felt like when Anthropic
launched Fable, people were overly
critical of them on their restrictions.
Uh, in that like I'm taking them and
open AAI at their word of like the bio
risks. I think that
>> I think that's fair.
>> I think that there's like risks there
and like
>> with those with like cyber security if
something gets through it's like ah it's
not great but okay. With like bio it's
like significantly more it's
significantly worse if something slips
through. if I like if some if something
slips through that I want to see these
tools available to everyone but at the
same time like I think that there are
like risks involved and like it's not
it's not fair to the companies to like
dog on them for putting in safeguards
for like technology that is like this
new that makes sense as long as
>> I think it's still fun to make
>> to poke at the trillion dollar company
it's okay a little bit little bit is
okay
>> they can take it they can take it
>> I think they can dig it
>> I think
It's not like my tweet is going to
change anything.
>> The like longtail impact of like
dropping everything down, but I'm also
guilty of this where I like did the
tweet of like
>> No, you've been doing it every day for
the long
>> I know you've been tweeting at peaked
every day
>> and now most recently uh
>> commerce secretary
>> commerce secretary Howard Lutnik.
>> Howard Lutnik like you've been asking
for access. Um,
>> no. The one that I did that I was like
not super happy with was the like
regulate me. Uh, it was like the we'll
get it up on the screen, but like it was
like um Claude saying regulate me to the
computer and then the computer was the
US government flag, the US flag, you're
being regulated and then
>> oh my god like oh my god that one I'm
just like oh it misses like the nuance
of the situation where like they've been
very hostile to like they've been very
hostile and it like seemed like the
safeguards like mostly been in place. We
need to get
>> Oh, listen. I I I do agree with you on
the security bio thing. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, but these are And
>> I don't want to like diss the model
companies at the model company factory
[laughter] fest, so to speak.
>> Yeah. Keep your voice down. Right over
there.
>> At this point, they should be dedicating
money into, for lack of a better word,
propaganda and spreading the good word
of AI. And because everyone is freaking
out, dude, like in normal land.
>> Oh, yeah. They're pissed at AI.
>> They are. So, Dude, data centers are
actually like overall good. It's fine.
Like we should be welcoming those.
>> There's been a really interesting
contrast between Anthropic and Open AAI
where I would say that the positioning
from Anthropic has been to like really
retreat from social media and like
public posting. And so you'll see these
like 2-year-old clips of Daario
circulate
>> and uh on the one hand like he's had
them, they're on the record, like it's
out there. Uh and so like that's the
impact of that. But at the same time
like a lot of similar things were said
from open AI but then in the like the
past 6 months they kind of changed a lot
of their positioning to be a bit more
like oh we're for like the humans we're
augmenting your work not replacing it.
Uh and so it's been interesting to see
those two those two different
positionings and how they worked out.
>> No one of the things I hear is like even
internally they have the exact same
conversation by the way which is it's
not a given that it's going to be one
way or the other. So if we actually try
to make things better for like
augmenting human thing and the CEOs are
like you know what considering that the
moat is not the model the model is not
the moat anymore. Yeah let's just help
people build great things.
>> I would also say like taking the like
open AI for the people like with a
[laughter] with a grain of salt and like
I don't know it's very difficult for me
to know what my job is going to be like
in a year's time. My only input on it is
one that if there is going to be a
degree of regulation on the models, I
don't want it done in the way it's being
done now. I want like actual experts
with real scientific process behind.
>> Sure.
>> I want more like transparency and rigor
behind how uh models are evaluated. I
don't think we have that figured out
yet. And if you're interested in kind of
this topic, uh, go find the conversation
that Lowlevel Learning hosted at Planet
Scale, uh, and listen to that.
Fantastic. Basically a full hour of this
conversation. So if you're into that,
the one other item I want to cover in
the news is that Sonnet 5.0 came out
just before we started.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> literally an article. Yeah. I don't have
too much to say on it other than like
hopefully the two things I hope from it
is that I don't know if it was rolled
out to limited partners or if it's also
banned. Uh and
>> it's full access.
>> It's full access.
>> And the other thing um is that I hope
that it has not followed suit in
anthropic
not supporting zero data retention. Uh
because
>> I think it is zero zero data retention.
>> It supports zero data retention. Yeah,
I'm pretty sure like throw it up, but
>> for context for listeners, zero data
retention is uh effectively a policy
when you're sending your prompts to
these providers that they they won't
retain and train on that data.
>> It's not even just prompts, it's like
your tool calls like private data,
everything. That's what makes it like
>> which is a huge if if not the most
important thing for a lot of enterprises
out there. So like Fable's just even
when it comes back, if it comes back.
>> Yeah. Oh, wait. Do you want to put like
a bet like by uh by the next episode 10
bucks does it
>> I mean I've been thinking it's going to
come back. I've been thinking it's it'll
be back each day. I'm like oh it'll come
back today.
>> I'll bet
>> since it was banned.
>> I'll bet 10 bucks that both GPT56 and
Fable is back by the time we do our next
record our next episode.
>> Okay. I'll take the counter on that. It
won't be back. 10 bucks. What about you?
I'll take the counter.
>> Desperate.
>> Yeah, I'm taking the counter that
they're not available.
>> They're not available.
>> I'm like I
I don't think we get Fable until 5 5.6
is like worse than Fable in the
benchmarks that they posted
>> which might be them benchmark hacking a
little bit where it's like well
>> sandbagging things.
>> Yeah. Uh but let's say that it is. It
would be weird for me for like Fable to
be general access before 5.6 is general
access
>> and from the communications we've had
from OpenAI on the 5.6 rollout
>> it sounds like it's going to be like
weeks. Uh, and so,
>> oh, sounds like I'm about to lose 10
bucks, 20 bucks.
>> My timeline's a late book.
>> July, late July. Fable coming back.
>> The first topic that we really want to
dive into today is basically I don't
want to use your products agent. I want
your product to enable my agent. And I
had a tweet that I said uh earlier
[music] in the week. I had retweeted a
tweet from Dax um where Dax had said,
"Everyone's happy to keep building agent
frameworks while ignoring every single
agent in the products they use." And I
quote tweeted that and said, "I don't
want to use your products, agent. I want
my agents to be efficiently enabled to
use your product." And uh Sunil and I
talked a little bit about this while we
were kind of planning out uh the
episode, but I think we are getting to a
point where I don't think we really knew
as an industry up until kind of recently
that like is everyone going to be using
a bunch of agents kind of all over the
place? How do you orchestrate and manage
them? Am I going to be using my own
agent and connecting and talking with
your agents? Am I just connecting to a
bunch of MCPs? And I think I've I've
I've pretty firmly fallen in the latter
camp there where like I think that the
ideal kind of workflow for both
engineers and you know someone sitting
in HR or a architect is they have an
agent on their local machine and
it is connecting to the services and the
products rather than going to like I
don't want to be going to my doc's
website and using their agent like I
don't even want to be going to
Cloudflare's like I hard I rarely ever
go to Cloudflare's
>> we have a good agent but
>> year we have a glow up on our dashboard
I am going there far less
>> enough people at the conference have
told me this they're like I'm so glad I
don't have to go to your dashboard
anymore and I'm like but we just made it
good like it just got good
>> y I just connect to the MCP and like I
want I still want good products and I
think uh I don't know if we talked about
this last time but I I've certainly said
this on my Twitch stream like I haven't
been
super excited about anything coming out
of the companies I follow for like the
past six months because it's all it's
all the same.
>> There's been like really no exciting
stuff uh in my opinion really coming
outside of the the model labs as far as
products. Like it's all just like agent
this, agent that. I want to get back to
people really differentiating their
products for what they're good at and
adding value to my life and my workflow
and my family and my dayto-day. And I
want all that data in one place, which
is like my underlying theory. And I
think this this is kind of a lot to do
with what you're building at YC with
executor like
>> oh that's just it. Either you build a
product that splits it out or you build
a thing that connects it all and like
helps you connect to other things.
That's the one you're building right
now.
>> If you're only ever going to use cloud
code, I actually don't know that
executor makes as much sense for like
that person. Um, it's the moment where
like you go to like use codecs or spin
up background agents or spin up like
not using the agents that exist in
products. Uh, like not using the agent
inside Cloudflare,
>> but like I'm using Flu and I'm deploying
a GitHub review bot to my company. I
want it to pull in the observability
data so it can go back and like look
through when it sees the when it sees
something in the PR. I want my agent to
be able to go look through historical
logs and understand, hey, what's the
impact of this? There's really
interesting things there around agent
identities also where it's like, oh
yeah, this agent is provisioned to this
account that can access these resources.
Something I I've just been like really
like pushing for companies to do um is,
you know, you're putting all this
investment and time into building an
agent for your company. And I actually
think that it does make sense for
companies to have an agent in their
dashboard. I'm sure if you like go to
the Cloudflare if you like look at the
Cloudflare agent analytics there's like
a non-zero amount of people that get a
significant
>> Oh no no no so people love it by the way
that's just it like the reason this
happens is because every human actually
doesn't have an agent right
>> yeah and so what I look look at is like
how do you scale agent tools to like a
billion people right how do you get like
everyone being able to
the way that I interact with websites is
so much better than how I had to before
because I can just tell an agent hey go
use the cloudfl CLI and do this and
that's in the background. it's not
taking up time in my space in my head.
And so it's like, okay, how do you get
that for all people? And there's like
varying levels of that. You'll have
people that are only ever going to use
chat GPT. You'll have people that like
actually really just want to use the
website, use like the agent in the
website like Cloudflare's agent. And
then you'll have like these superpower
users that are like running Claude code
or like have or codeex like on their
computer running PI and need to get all
of that same context, tools, and skills
into their agent. So, one of the one of
the goals with Cloudflare agent in
particular is to eventually
make it accessible in your own harness
and likely expose it probably over MCP
and that way like you can get uh
essentially the capabilities of like
we've effectively built a harness
underneath of the agent to do very
Cloudflare specific things and it's all
wraps around Cloudflare MCP. Surely you
could just use CloudFire MCP, but you
know the the agent experience team has
been putting a lot of work into actually
making it very good at doing like common
CloudFire workflows. Do you think if a
company is prioritizing like agents,
should it be exposable over something
like MCP or another protocol in your own
harness
>> which is different from like our
existing MCP server which is the raw
tools.
>> The way I think about these things is a
couple things. I'll go down a bunch of
different threads. One is making all of
your to making everything you can do in
your product agent accessible whether
that's your internal agent or external
agents. That looks like making your
entire open API spec callable by agents.
Uh supporting dynamic registration so
like client ID metadata documents.
That's the first thing is getting an
agent that has access to your whole API
surface and also keeping the user in the
loop for like destructive actions is
another one.
>> That's like the first thing is making
that agent accessible. The next thing is
your product likely has a lot of hostile
APIs to like people that aren't
unfamiliar with it. If you think about
how a front end works, a lot of what the
jobs a front end does is data
preparation to go into an API. It might
be that you like select something from a
list like it prepares the data and then
you select select from a list or it
infers from one endpoint sends it to
another. That's actually where I view
MCP as being really important is your
API spec exists. agents should be able
to call it. And then MCP exists as this
subset of like more complicated flows
and actions that's like centri is an
interesting example of this where I
think they're working on um running
small models in their search that takes
what query you're trying to do and like
does that query on your behalf and so
you're like invoking inference but I
believe it's like pretty cheap for them
to serve and like your agent now doesn't
have to figure out that whole uh flow.
So that's also where I think exposing to
other agents are really interesting. And
then the last thing is on how you
actually like structure your um in
company agent and your like external
skills MCP.
When you're building an agent for your
company, I feel really strongly that you
should build that on top of the same MCP
server and skills that you are
distributing to your end users because
then you only have like one source of
truth to maintain. Yep.
>> Uh and like you're not maintaining two
different product segments too. That's a
bit information.
>> One of the uh the things I was really I
helped start the project for
CloudFlire's AJ. And one of the things
that we were like dead set adamant about
is that we didn't want to give that
agent a bunch of like internal APIs or
access that like our customers couldn't
use through our APIs, our MCP, etc. And
we use that almost as like a forcing
function or a flywheel because we're
we're keeping tracks with eval and other
metrics on how the agent is responding
to all the hundreds of products that
Cloudflare has. And we have we can see
where is the agent struggling with R2?
Is the agent giving really good advice
and succeeding in building apps with
durable objects? And if the agent
struggles on any one of those things,
it's a good sign that our docs or our
skills are not good enough and then we
can go and improve those. That feeds
back makes the agent better. We get
updated,
>> you know, information about how AI is
doing with using Cloudflare in general.
And it's just this nice little flywheel.
I think uh uh Anker Goyle from Brain
Trust had a decent tweet around this
topic where he said there are two
interesting mega trends right now. Uh
one being rework my company to operate
with agents and rework my product to be
an a uh an agent. Uh requires a ton of
discipline to not conflate these not
much room for horizontal agent
platforms. I had kind of responded uh I
said the trend for most companies should
be rework my company to operate with
agents and rework my products to work
well with uh our customers agents. So
again kind of going back to like what
>> covered a little bit. I want to dive in
maybe a little bit more for a couple
minutes on like what makes a product
good for agents. And timely enough to
that, uh, Lenny Press from Amplify put
out a an amazing
>> such a good post
>> article today called the primitive is
the product and
he basically opines on like uh, you
know, what actually makes something good
for agents to use. and he he talks about
how Hashi Corp works and how you want to
focus on primitives and there's a few
paragraphs in particular I want to call
out and read here. Uh he goes on to say
uh first and foremost teams need to stop
thinking in terms of features and
prescriptive workflows and start
thinking in terms of abstractions and
capabilities. Features are a liability
for agents. Every feature expands the
decision space an agent must reason
about. More features mean more edge
cases, more ambiguity, and more failure
modes. At best, this translates into
higher token spend and at worst into
busted agent behavior. Agents naturally
gravitate towards the smallest stable
abstraction. So in an agent first world,
the most important question facing
product teams is not what features and
why, but instead how do I design the
right primitives? So I'm I'm curious on
your take on that because that blends a
lot into what you were kind of
discussing earlier about kind of what
makes something agent ready. So like how
how does that resonate with you like
building executor and thinking about
primitives?
>> It resonates pretty heavily though like
one thing I would maybe say is sometimes
you have to ship something to understand
what the primitives you need to build
off. Like I got into like this rut with
executor for like two weeks where I was
like trying to think think through what
the right primitives are, what the right
thing to build is.
picked
everything
or migrate this, but like I actually
like understand better what the thing
is. But I actually think that Cloudflare
is a much better like thing to compare
to there where if you could imagine
Cloudflare
launching today like you wouldn't have
D1 wouldn't have like and you guys were
kind of changing some of these now like
you wouldn't have uh pages you probably
just have like workers and durable
objects
>> and docs on how you compose them but not
like the actual core products which is
really interesting. I mean
>> I mean you can push back on that but
>> well no specifically with pages we did
have this conversation back at the time
when we did build
>> thing and no push back it was very much
a humans want something like simple that
they can like latch on to let's do it
for the majority use case I mean the
drama there wasn't even around a
separate product it's that there are a
bunch of other companies that build the
same thing that also uh are cloudflare
customers and in the beginning they felt
threatened but it turned out it was just
a completely different product like I
don't think we actually ate anyone's
traffic or use case
>> I think with how products look now and
how AI is able to write code and
>> yeah that's how I would design right now
>> I I very very strongly feel on like what
is the I like love the pi approach of
like what is the base thing that you can
like make extendable by your customers
>> I think that's kind of what Lenny was
getting at in this article like
>> give the solid
>> foundation to your product and if it
fits well it's going to enable more
composition on top of that and
>> okay the the counter to this very much
is in the developer world agents have
found PMF such that every developer has
uh a hardness that they use to interact
with these things
>> uh Apple and Google have dropped the
ball so hard on this which means that
normies have no idea what we're talking
about when we say we this thing because
I mean that's how psychosis happens
right which is a normie gets access to
cloud code uh and and the $200 plan and
they're like three nights deep without a
shower and they're like I am a golden
god like
>> dude that's just Reese waiting for Fable
to come.
>> That's not me. That's my uh dad vibe
coding with blood codes.
>> Insanity. Uh no, we've spoken about this
like one of the things that happens not
in a bunch of companies but even in
Cloudflare is some of management got AI
psychosis.
>> Yeah. and they kind of disappeared for 2
days and we were like, "Okay, we need
them to get off the high, find rock
bottom and then come back to us." It
absolutely happens. I sort of look at
like the long longer horizons when it
with some of these things where I'm like
it hasn't reached mass adoption yet but
like the capabilities are there and so I
like look at like the 5year time scale
where I'm like okay like this see does
seem like like direction this seems like
where things are going um in terms of
like
>> so do you think some capabilities like
that those capabilities will be
generally available? No, no, no. So you
you take the premise that you made which
is uh if you were designing a phone
today, you would build it to be almost
agent first and apps are just
capabilities that you like reach for.
>> Oh, interesting.
>> Um
>> do you think Google
>> what what makes something agent first?
And what it and one of the things that
Lenny talks about in this article is
that like one of the conclusion I guess
he draws is that what's good for
developers is also what's good for
agents.
>> Sure.
>> Do you agree with that?
>> Whenever I see something that's like
marketed as like for agents, I get a
little skeptical
>> where I'm like, can this stand on its
own two feet as like
>> Yeah. I think there's a ton of hype and
there.
>> And and so with
>> Okay, let's let's get narrow in on this.
Oh,
>> like what concretely makes an API?
Let's just let's narrow it down to an
API and CLI and maybe maybe MCP, but
let's focus on APIs and CLIs right now.
What makes one of these because they're
generally the way agents are interacting
with our services and products? What
makes what makes one of them good? I I I
think in my opinion, it is very easy to
discover documentation. In fact, I think
>> sure
>> the Asher team with flu uh they built
like docs into their CLI and it is like
I've watched my agent tried to build flu
stuff uh uh versel shipping Eve they
have like the documentation bundled in
with the install like I think things
like that really make a difference and
like like looking back when I was a
younger dev like I wish I would have had
like if that would have made it easier
for me back then too like
discoverability read the docs thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's like kind of supporting
the thesis that like what's good for
developers is good for agents.
>> So I think like code mode breaks that
assumption by the way. So what's good
for the agent there is very much to
write code against the interface.
>> Yeah.
>> But that's not a way developer wants to
interface.
>> But is that an implementation detail
though?
>> So I would actually say that that's like
not new where I would like think about a
world before agents and it's like you
would still want a well doumented open
API spec. No. So
>> because people want to like write
automations on your platform. So we had
a we have a massive API surface and our
first version of our MCP servers were
domain specific individual MCP servers
and we have like a big team maintaining
it and then Matt Carrie comes and says h
two tools sorry that's what it is all
the tools all the time 100 tokens and
now we're saying like code mode is the
future of like interacting like with API
so I look I'm not saying like that's
like a complete dealbreaker because now
like it's in the middle instead of being
like the actual API
>> I don't know to look at like the
primitives where it's like the thing
that hasn't changed here.
>> None of this would be possible if
Cloudflare didn't have a good open back.
>> That's what I was saying back to the
primitives. It's like even like when I
think about like what makes sense like
uh I had this with skills where to me
skills are just docs and good docs have
always mattered and skills are an
extension of your doc skills are an
extension of your docs.
>> Is it do you think Mac OS is a better
programming surface than Linux? I feel I
could do my job equally on
>> No, we're saying like literally things
better for like developers versus Mac OS
is kind of like locked down, but it is
well designed.
>> I don't know.
>> But to to Reese's point, like what makes
Cloudflare good is that we have these
>> hundreds of API surfaces to interact
with our products,
>> right? and that we have it documented in
an open API spec and that we have I mean
I think we could do a much better job
here we're working on it but like I
think another important thing is really
good errors the more context I mean I've
I'll die on this hill even before
>> because your error message should tell
you what to do next
>> include contextual information on error
messages to get to the agent
>> next I I guess I just like view this
stuff as like a given and like these are
like what you you do like this is how
you like build good products is you
clear error messages like this is it's
not how you build a good product for AI,
it's how you build a good product in
general and it's also maybe like why MCP
like had like a rough start is we were
trying to make something for agents not
for like humans or not we were like
looking at it from the perspective of
like oh make it from for agents when you
can like look at it more from a
perspective of like what like are the
things that people use today how do you
get them exposed to agents uh
>> so you're coming to the same conclusion
then ultimately that nothing has really
changed in building good products.
>> Yeah.
>> Kind of that like what's good for what
what has always been good for
>> Well, no, that's just it. You actually
don't need to design human workflows
anymore. That's part of the outcome of
this, right? Like if you're saying you
don't do features anymore. You just do
>> I think that's his argument for like
building and focusing on the
>> but that's the that's the primit like
that would be the Cloudflare API that's
a Cloudflare API spec versus like
Labyrinth. Oh, so which is what we're
like we're like, "Oh, maybe you wouldn't
design the dashboard at all today if
you're doing an infra company."
>> That's how I've always developed anyways
is that like when I'm building a new
product or a feature, I want to start at
thinking about how users are going to
access that data
>> and I want to think about the access
patterns. I'll die on the hill that
products live or die by the database. If
I don't plan if I don't have to explain
to a single person after this what a
durable object is, that would be a win
for me, right? But I'm like, just ask
your agent to read the docs
>> cuz you can like if you start building
from like the UI down and you make a
bunch of bad assumptions about how
people are going to use your your
product or access the data, it might not
matter at smaller levels, but you scale
up to a Versel size, a Cloudflare size,
a you know a giant Fortune 500 company
size, and suddenly
you're talking about like even with
agents month-long, multimonthlong
refactors and data migrations. And like
if you start at that level and nail the
primitives, you give yourself a much
better foundation to build off of.
Anyone more thoughts on on this before
we we pivot?
>> No, it's uh I would just like stress
that company like I don't want to use
the agents that companies build. Oh, I
have like one I'll see if I can do this
in a minute. The like last thing that I
would say is like I want my agent to not
just have like a company's APIs uh but I
also want it to have like the knowledge
and skills and like expertise that that
company has
>> and so I'll use um I'll use postto and
linear as the examples. Um, so like
Postto like so much work has been put
into their dashboard widgets to help you
understand their documentation to help
you understand this is how you do
growth, this is how you like measure
your analytics. And so the exact same
thing if you can like expose that as
like skills or documentation to your
agents and let them autonomous let them
like leverage all of the knowledge you
built up I think is a really
underexplored area of like creating like
a bringing in an expert that like runs
on your own inference or your own stack.
Oh, by the way, to answer your question
though, there is a reason why everyone's
building an agent and why everyone is
building agent frameworks, myself
included, because they believe that if
they are top of the funnel, they can
slice off one cent of every dollar and
capture the value while schlubs who
build out real products and put hard
work into it do the real work. Dax had
an interesting reply to me on this one
that was like as a user 100% I want this
but like companies are not going to be
happy giving up like that's
>> giving up having users in their product
and like you're like disconnecting users
from your product.
>> Yeah. They want to like lock you in and
sell you on the brand and now they have
to that's just it like and is there
going to be like paid API access like uh
>> I do think that's one thing that will
probably change is like a combination of
API access getting more expensive.
>> Sure. And also like I I think especially
I see this using our own MCP server like
we're I think the world is going to have
to like
>> deal with increasing rate limits because
agents are hitting stuff so much more
frequently.
>> GitHub is the best example of this
is I think it's like 13x usage or
something. It was earlier it's much
higher now already. Rita has a great
talk and some writing on like right now
the world's worried about like GPU and
memory spend, but like if we keep going
in this trajectory of agents taking over
everything, like we're going to have to
worry about CPUs, too.
>> Yeah, that's interesting. Yeah. Wow.
>> Storage. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
>> We'll save that for a for another
conversation. So, the next topic I kind
of uh want to dive back into is round
two for loops and software factories.
I'm going to start this off with an
article that Armen uh of Arendelle and
Pi famously the creator
>> the creator
>> the creator of pi
>> that's right
>> Armen uh
>> did are you saying Armen is the one who
created Pi
>> yeah that is canon now
>> that is canon
>> yes
>> have you heard about this
>> the loop or the oh the creator of yes
I'm a creative pie and for anyone that
>> and also actually I mean I use flask was
the first thing that I used And that was
made by um
>> by Mario. Is that correct?
>> By Mario. Yeah, exactly. Mario, the
creator of Flask famously.
>> Yeah.
>> So anyways, uh he wrote an article that
everyone should read. Armen's writing is
like some of the most highquality
fantastic writing in tech I think at the
moment. He has just a way of blending
his uh kind of thoughts and feelings
with objectiveness and like it's just
stellar. And so he wrote an article
called the coming loop. And my read on
this article and some of the conclusions
I think he draws is like he and Mario
and Arendelle are obviously maintaining
in building pi which is a very minimal
coding harness. It's what I use. I I
value the minimalism of this
>> tools tiny prompt and it rips.
>> Yep. It's amazing. I love it. And it
it's made me sensitive to like like it's
part of the reason I uh had stopped
using open code is because like I think
Dax in the team is incredibly talented
and open code is amazing but even just
like the week to week tweaks in the
system prompt and how tools are loaded
or how skills work like those things
affect the the performance and the
characteristics of models and like
>> especially for a thing you're spending
12 hours a day in type
>> right I want to reduce the amount ount
of non-determinism as possible which is
why I I really value Pi and okay so
anyways he writes this this article what
was the title the coming loop and in
this article like as we talked about in
our our first episode like
he is not bought into the world where we
are having our agents write loops to go
do all these things and he you can see
this in his GitHub you can see this in
his tweets like he's experimented with
it like he's someone that I I think
people should pay attention to in this
face, but he also gets at in this
article. I think like he can see a world
where there is more of this and like he
kind of wrestles with like he's not at a
point where he feels comfortable
adopting these workflows. I think at the
moment there's not a place in Pi quite
yet for these, but he sees a world where
that might be in Pi. And I I think he's
they're kind of wrestling with like when
when do you start evolving Pi to have
these?
>> No. Because because Pi is hackable, it
means that if they don't come up with an
opinion for it, someone else will.
>> Yeah.
>> And everyone is driven to finding out an
answer to this right now because it
seems like such a utopian world of
running uh what loops are we talking
about? Are we talking about the like
development loop where you auto do
autonomous QA? Are we talking about like
an entire loop where you're ingesting
feedback from Slack into watching the
different
>> I think this is kind of like
holistically and like this came this is
now like a week or two old and it came
out right after both Boris and Peter had
been tweeting about
>> you know their loop tweets
>> but I don't know that Peter Oaris ever
clarified what they I I know Boris has
clarified more
>> Boris yeah no Boris is talking about
likeloop or goal like those are the
things that they're talking Oh,
interesting.
>> And I think dynamic workflows too,
>> right?
>> Exactly.
>> No, I want to I want to read some of the
the end of this article here. Today, I
do not like much of the code that I see
from systems built uh that way, and
neither do I enjoy interacting with too
much of software built with AI
assistance. Looping is powerful, but it
removes responsibility more and more.
And it at least today very much
encourages us to give into the machine.
And yet I have no doubts that this
looping future is going to be our
future. Despite the fact that I
presently resent it, I already see
astonishingly small teams building at
impossible se speed. And I see code
bases turning more and more into obscure
and confusing organisms that can only be
diagnosed by more machines. Those code
bases are simultaneously useful and
messy. So I guess I'm coming to terms
with the that the question is not
whether we will loop because clearly we
will. Maybe the question is that in a
future of loops, how do we not abdicate
judgment, how we can retain rules of
good engineering, how we can ensure that
responsible uh humans can continue to
supervise, how we need to rethink how we
architect code to retain sanity like
along the way. And I think since we last
talked about this topic, I have dialed
in my workflow and have a very
consistent workflow. And again, we'll
we'll talk about this more next time,
but I am very hands-on with my agent in
guiding it and exactly what I wanted to
implement and then getting in a tight
review loop on the code it writes until
it's in a place I'm happy with. All
right.
>> But one of the most annoying and tiring
things, the thing that exhausts me more
than anything that regardless of the
amount of work I put in up front to
planning, writing a good text spec using
type- driven development and making
outline the call stack and this that and
the other like I always catch myself
repeating the same things in code review
and finding the same mistakes. And one
thing I've started doing because that is
so exhausting to do for every feature
and every, you know, little thing I'm
building is I've tried to capture what I
consider good principles of software
design into skills. And I have this on
my GitHub if anyone wants to go look. I
can't say one way or the other if these
are good and work or not yet. I've tried
to take as much inspiration as possible
from my hook skills, which I think are
are very good. But like I can see a
world or I'm trying to at least move my
workflow to a place where like that
first pass at reviewing an
implementation is done by like an
optimized
agent that knows how to review code for
the things I care about and for the
things that I am most frequently
correcting it on. So I can see this
world where like I have like a queue of
some sort that when an agent finishes an
implementation, a message gets put into
a queue, maybe an issue gets put into a
tracker, it doesn't really matter, and
then another agent is just monitoring
that, picking up and doing a first pass,
and then after that first pass puts in
another queue for me to review.
>> There's so many thoughts.
>> Let rip.
>> Me and someone on the Codeex team were
like talking past each other on Twitter
for 6 months where
>> I can't see you doing that at all. I was
tweeting out like these models are
terrible. Like they don't they're not
like they just output bad code. He was
like well they're junior engineers. You
have to teach them like they're junior
engineers. And I'm like they're not
junior engineers. they're outputting
they're not like the the mistakes that
they're making are not things that I can
solve through like in this way where
like they're talking past each other
happen is I he had a tweet recently that
was like when they work when the models
work in a codebase like they have no
long-term planning or long-term like
vision of what the codebase is building
to
>> y
>> and I replied to him and I was like yes
exactly uh but what was funny is I had
the exact same realization of like what
he was saying like a month before that
where I was like, "Oh, if I codify when
I get a bug that's like affect not
optimistically updating correctly."
>> Yeah,
>> that's actually information that I can
codify in a skill commit to the
codebase. When you look at these things
on a small scale, if you give it a code
snippet and say, does it match this
concept? It like is it it I can pretty
pretty confidently say that it will be
able to on a small scale do that
correctly. And so you end up like with
the loops you end up building this like
house of cards or like house of
inference where house of I like it
>> where you just like you stack more and
more onto it and you're like replacing
these like good engineering patterns to
make good software with more and more
inference loops trying to make it
better. I sort of view it as like we've
been making these artisal handw chairs
for years and now someone's invented a
machine that someone's in someone's
invented IKEA and like the the quality
is not as good but like more chairs are
accessible to more people and what does
that look like in the long term? So the
push back here is by the way there are
so many I don't even want to use the
word entrepreneurs but people who build
massive uh consulting companies I don't
want to take any names on here who've
been trying this for the last 30 40
years like Java exists as a language
because they are like can we make a
language that basically is guardrails as
syntax. Yeah,
>> they do. It's a terrible way to like
build it itself because they were like,
"Oh, if we can do that and we establish
best uh best practices for the industry
and we call it enterprise net beans or
something like that and you throw bodies
at the problem."
>> Uh you end up with a software factory
like this is so everyone is looking at
AI these same people who run these shops
are looking at AI as like oh can I
encode this? Uh we talk about this on
the agents team all the time which is
that the role of code has kind of
changed. Uh software used to be a thing
that lets you achieve something but now
it lets you uh get leverage for a
particular moment in time. And we have
this code generation machine that can
spit out uh let's say 90 we we keep
throwing that number out there 90% of
something that makes it like work that
gets them the deal that gets them uh
achieve the features that they want to
and they're moving on to like the next
thing. big reason with the loops like
anytime you're discussing about look I I
I want to dial it in so that it's
accurate uh people are more worried
about dialing it in so uh it so that
they can get away with shipping it if
that makes sense this passes some
arbitrary
coding standard sock 2 compliance will
be the skill that they add in it make
sure that every access data access is
behind a stupid OM that locked all of
that that is like the software factory
that people are trying to building.
They're not trying to build something
that's good.
>> How does that change our role? Let's say
Armen is correct. Uh which I I I feel
very aligned with what he wrote in that
that piece. Um
>> Oh, actually Armen's a great example
because Flask was written as a counter
to Django.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Uh and Flask is beautiful and
engineers love it. Uh but people use
Django to like build businesses and
e-commerce sites and all that because
they're like we kind of know how it
works. There are dogs for setting up a
gallery and I'm not going to sit and
it's sort of like what's the role of
code like wait like it's like what's
what's the role of code and like what is
our job as software engineers something
I've been like coming around to a little
bit is like actually my job is not to do
the so it's like two things I'm going to
say something and then immediately
disagree with it. Uh it like it to an
extent our job is not to write make the
most beautiful codebase. Our job is like
to do to solve a problem for people and
if that problem is solved in a way that
like works for them and like doesn't
frustrate like if if it solves their
problem then they like couldn't care
less how it's implemented on the hut. At
the same time, the whole reason I ended
up caring so much about how code is
written and like why I care about
effect, why I care about all these
different concepts. Yep.
>> Is because I really believe that you
build good software or you I really
believe that like your ability to build
good software and um continue to develop
a product that people love. All comes
down from like the state of your
codebase and the quality of that.
>> Uh fully agreed.
>> And so you but like this is a thing that
we've had for forever. Like I I kind of
come back to like
>> nothing's new under the sun.
>> Nothing's new. Like tech debt like tech
debt isn't a new thing.
>> No.
>> Like
>> like it's like a real purpose.
>> You can like and you can take on you
it's like it's debt. You take on debt,
you pay it off and like you balance that
>> you balance that out.
>> I wanted to talk about this in our next
segment for our receipt segment where we
uh hold both uh others on the internet
and ourselves accountable to hot takes.
Um, one of the things I want to get into
there, I I guess to quickly wrap up the
section on loops, I think it sounds like
we're kind of in consensus that that is
probably kind of like Armen is saying in
this article, it's it's where we're
going, but I don't think we're there yet
quite today.
>> You don't have the tech. Um but it's
something that it's probably worth at
least
>> no I can tell you uh four out of five
people who are attending this conference
not as a developer but maybe the
developers as well are looking to build
software factories and every single
company on the expo floor wants to be in
the critical path like even just a tiny
slice of it.
>> Yeah. I I actually think my like
practical advice here would be like do
not start at the position of trying to
build an automated software factory like
dial in in a a workflow with your agents
that you can find some degree of
consistency regardless of model and
harness. That's right.
>> And then once you get to that point that
will probably take a bunch of tokens and
a bunch of frustrations. I know it did
for me. Once you get to a point where
you have some degree of consistency with
these dynamic stoastic models, then when
you find yourself hitting the points
where you're saying or doing the same
thing almost like word for word in your
prompts, that's where you can start
thinking about introducing these these
automations and these loops. I saw I saw
a great tweet by Shad Cen where he's
like all the bestlaid plans by models
are destroyed by two by three words. Are
you sure? I like that. Moving on to our
receipts section. There's two new
tweets. One returning person that I I
want to put some uh accountability to a
new person that has not uh appeared yet.
>> Sure.
>> Mario, you're safe this time. Uh but
we're we're on the lookout. Mario's
doing like dad core tweets and you don't
call them out of that right now.
>> We'll find one. We'll find one. So, the
first one actually comes from uh Theo.
Uh I pulled this one out and Theo Brown
had said, "I'd estimate we're about 6
months away from most devs moving their
code agents off their laptops."
Agree? Disagree? You think it's a good
prediction?
>> It's actually like a very easy one
because he's not saying your workflow
changes. He's just saying that you're
running it on another machine and it's
going to take he says 6 months but
probably 3 months for the tooling and
the thing for that to like work out. But
uh today actually announced the new
version of their coding agent. It's
called Orbs. I don't know if you see
this.
>> I have not seen it yet.
>> So it's a a transparent layer where
you're typing this stuff out but it is
actually running on the cloud but it it
feels extremely local uh uh local coding
experience.
>> I don't know you. So, my remote setup
>> uh
>> Yeah, your remote setup lost us a
competition.
>> I know. Um
>> I've heard.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Unbelievable.
>> The I don't know. I tried to do a remote
setup uh for like 6 months and it like
worked fine, but there was a bunch of
issues and it was kind of annoying.
There's just this long tale of things
that's like, "Oh yeah, I downloaded the
logs to my downloads folder. Go get it."
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. that it doesn't
capture like for for workflows to go to
cloud.
>> There's a lot of blockers involved in
that and like the the the problem isn't
actually compute or like uh the problem
is the dev setup.
>> Exactly.
>> And like you have to get your app to be
able to run with no environment
variables and like really good preview
deployments all this stuff. Emulate by
VLE absolutely incredible for that.
>> Beautiful.
>> I a production I want to say.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yep. So, I have a host of
>> single-handedly putting the Age of
Agentic tooling in his backpack.
>> It's incredible. I didn't My like agent
went off and made like a work OS
emulator and I didn't even like notice
that this didn't even like realize that
this was possible, but it subbed out the
login screen and so now my app can run
without those environment variables,
which was like huge for being able to
like send an agent off and be like,
"Hey, there's this one bug in the cloud
product. Go debug it." So, yeah, I'd
agree. I would I'm like hesitant. I
think that like what it more looks like
is the part that has to be solved first
is autonomous QA and uh running the dev
server like there's that like long tail
of problems but I could see it by the
way again Sun Microsystems did this in
the late '90s early 2000s thin clients
this is uh
>> they're just going to bring it all back
developers in banks and your JP Morgans
etc. they get a laptop and then they
spin up a Citrix uh VM machine where
you're running Windows on VMware
somewhere or the other.
>> I think I I think that what's changed is
like the ability to adopt these things
has just exponentially gotten better
like like having a subdow work OS
emulator is incredible like and I would
never have put the time in to that
before.
>> I think I'm inclined to agree with Theo.
I think the biggest barrier is, as you
called out, the the tooling to make it
to give the same kind of experience that
I can get with local dev remote
environment. I would bet
>> that we'll probably see that move, I
think.
>> Uh the next one is from our good friend
Boris at Anthropic. He had a tweet uh
where he basically said that he thinks
there's going to be five arc types in uh
teams in the future. and he said that
they're going there's going to be
prototypers. Those who come up with
brand new ideas turn out many ideas most
of which don't ship. Builders quickly
turns a prototype or idea into
production grade uh infra. A sweeper
someone who cleans up UI simplifies the
code and system unchips optimizes
performance. A grower takes a product
that has been built and iterates on it
to improve product market fit. And a
maintainer owns a mature system to make
it secure, reliable, fast, and
efficient.
>> Imagine being the maintainer.
>> You say that and I were talking about
this beforehand.
>> Just a Dungeons and Dragons ass tweet,
dude. First of all, it's like a like a
skill sheet or whatever. The second is
there's no way that a let's say like
Cloudfire puts out a jobre saying we're
looking for a senior grower on our team.
>> I think I'm going to defend Boris a
little bit here that
>> go on
>> in that. Okay, I rolled my eyes six
months ago when all the labs started
like taking away the the the roles of
software engineer as titles and product
managers and everyone was getting
members.
>> I think that's growers these AI
companies.
>> Hear me out. Hear me out. Hear me out.
Hear me out. I think members of the
technical staff is probably more
directionally accurate over the the mid
to long term than than these titles. And
we can get into that another time. I've
ranted on Twitter about this. But also
like I if I had to build a team today
and I could compose it in any way, I
think I would build it around having
juniors and mid-level devs largely
respons responsible for doing the first
pass at implementing features and like
really focusing on shipping the first
pass. And this does not mean like not
reading the code, not taking time to
make sure it's Q8 and stuff, but putting
them on the front line to get stuff
shipped and then having what I like to
call software gardening. Uh I'm a
gardener of the codebase where
>> co term like I've heard it now a couple
of times.
>> Like I because it is so much easier to
make changes to code and people are
certainly less tied to code than they
used to be. Like it used to be like you
know if you want to go change other
people's code like you it could
sometimes be taboo and then in today's
age like people were far less tied to
their code. So like getting that first
implementation out and then cleaning up
get it stable make sure error logging is
good observability is good it's
performant the architecture and
abstractions are good kind of reserved
for the more senior folks. I don't know.
I think I think that would be an
interesting way to work.
>> Yeah. Do you really think you wouldn't
build a you wouldn't build new features
if you were like more senior? Like
wouldn't you be doing all five of those
roles? Like by the way those map onto
like existing things. Prototypers are
like designers in an engineering heavy
company. There's all maintainers are
like QA teams etc etc. Like I said, it's
just to an extent, this is how I've
always worked where I like really enjoy
going across the stack and like either
like trying to come up with
>> like what I'm saying is I'm calling
on this specific one. Yeah, I I
know you're positive on it, but me, I'm
like
>> super I don't think it
>> it's those five archetypes, but I do
think there is a a world where like
>> like I said, I that's how I would want
to try and build a team right now
because I think that is how I could
iterate with a group of developers to
build software the fastest and keep it
reliable. That's my my take.
>> I have no idea where things are go. I
don't know that I agree with that. I
don't know that I agree with the tweet.
I don't
>> I just don't agree.
>> I don't I don't know what things are
gonna I I think it all any predictions
>> I don't think I'm wrong. I think like
>> I I think specializations do change.
>> I I think it doesn't make sense to make
predictions like that in that could
loops not like with what they're trying
to do. Could could I not have a maintain
a loop and uh like
>> I guess it is kind of it is kind of
contradictory with his tweets from the
week before.
>> Oh yeah. So that's Boris. I think we're
2-1 on that. We've decided that you're
positive, but sure.
>> You pulled the tweet bogus. That's how
you end up in the maintainer position.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> I'm I'll be the idea guy shipping my
>> using your G brain and that's you're the
return of the idea guy. You the
technical co-founder to
>> um do your thing for you.
>> All right. To to close things out, uh I
don't know if you guys have any
predictions to make that you you want to
track, but I I have one that I want to I
want to get on the record. Uh my hot
take uh that we need receipts for is uh
I think that codecs and plug code start
gating and moving more functionality out
of their harnesses and into the cloud
and behind API access because I don't
think their models are remote and I
think building good harness features is
one of the only ways that they're going
to be able to kind of lock people into
their ecosystems going forward. So
you're already seeing this like I think
like OpenAI's acquisition of ONA was
like a sign on was get pod. So I assume
they're going to make like execution
environments for that but not in front
of the model but actually like behind
the model as an execute tool or a run
tool or something like that. They're
already doing this. They were already
shipping web search etc etc. I don't
know how much money they plan on making
for it but definitely in the sense of
stickiness and out ofthe-box usefulness.
Yeah. Yeah, I think you have to look at
something like computer use. You have to
look at emulate and you have to look at
computer use. You have to see how good
computer use is getting at like being
able to autonomously test stuff. How
good emulator is at being able to create
these test environments. And so the
factor of those two gets rid of that
like need to have things locally on your
computer. I feel like I don't know
enough about the games behind the scenes
to
like be able to be like,
>> but it makes sense.
>> Yeah. Also, as you get into like really
fast models, like less latency between
is probably like going to be a selling
point. Um, maybe you end up on like
discounted inference or something
because I mean what each turn each turn
with tool calling takes 100 milliseconds
round trip.
>> I'm not going to try to pretend like I
know the answer here.
>> You could offer a discounted fast mode
if you're running it in the same data
center the GPUs are in. Uh, because
you're doing inference right on the
right next to it, which is interesting.
Do either of you have a hot take today?
>> The one that I'm thinking about probably
just because of myself is uh number of
people who are going to have mental
breakdowns by working way too hard.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh will spike probably around
Thanksgiving etc. like around the later
part of the year. I think like summer's
here now the sun's out etc. As the
weather starts getting worse and AI
psychosis like kicks in across more like
>> once Ree gets fable back. Once I get
fable back.
>> Once you get fable back. Like I think
like insurance claims will jump. Mental
health stuff. Offices will start having
uh more meta used to do this like little
pods that you can take naps in.
>> Napping pods. The return of the napping
pods.
>> Well, Meta is bringing back their snack
counters is what I heard.
>> There was a really good Chzian tweet on
this. He was like, "Oh, the tools are
supposed to make us faster or make us
work less, but everyone's working
everyone I know is like working harder."
>> Yep. 100%. Um, the AI tools I feel like
have really shifted the relationship of
work. Like I would like slam my head
against a problem for like a workday and
then go home and be exhausted and then
like, oh, it'll click the next day.
Whereas like with the AI stuff, you kind
of just like push through it, but like
you don't know that you're pushing
through it
>> and it's very easy to like ignore a
little Oh, there have been times where
I'm like falling asleep and I'm like,
"Okay, I just need to type out the
prompt and hit enter and then
>> and it's actually really like I mean the
way I I do actually think that there's
like a funny overlap between LLMs and
gambling. Like every prompt is just like
a spin at the slot machine.
>> You got like Yeah, maybe I can get
>> We should probably do a full episode.
One of our core points is like mental
health and AI usage.
>> Let's let's plan on doing that. Do you
have any hot takes for the episode? My
like closing would be two. Um, one would
be one I tweeted out forever ago, which
was more companies go to be API first.
Uh, more like discoverability around
that. And I'm like very hopeful that
they implement something like CIMD,
dynamic client registration, like anyone
can authenticate to it. And then the
other one is loops aren't bad that
they're loops aren't bad, they're
different. Uh, it's a way of creating
like different products. You're like
playing this house of cards of inference
where it actually like you're playing
this cards of inference where at this
one tweet where it was this valley of
despair where if you're just prompting
normally it's actually a really bad
place to be in comparison to writing by
hand or like full agentic. There's like
kind of an other side of that valley
where it's like you have a bunch of
inference, you have agents monitoring
your deploys, you have them monitoring
your analytics, you have them autofixing
and it's like a completely different
type of software engineering. I don't
know that it's it's not bad. It's
different.
>> Reese, I'm gonna have to tell you what a
hot take is. It's not meant to be
nuanced and like [laughter]
>> supposed to cause drama.
>> Okay. Loops of the future.
Websites are done.
>> There you go. That's what I'm [laughter]
>> All right. Thank you everyone for tuning
in. Please let us know what you want to
hear us yap about. Uh our next episode
we're going to deep dive on each of our
workflows and how we actually do work
dayto-day brain set up. Oh my see in
their Twitter. I'm like I really excited
to see you guys.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think all three of us have
wildly different ways we work with AI.
So uh tune in then. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thanks again to organizers.
>> Yeah. Thank you so much for having us
record on the floor. Have a great
conference everyone. Thank go team. Go
team.
hate you. I was on a roll. We've
lost him, dude. La.
>> I'm tall, too. Okay. I'm not tall.
>> Called the first episode. Episode zero.
>> You're going to make me do this again.
>> Index zero. Episode one. Tell me what to
say.
>> I don't know.
>> Welcome to the next token. Nope. Nope.
Nope. I screwed it up.